Austin Wiley

Email: austinwiley84@gmail.com | Phone: 303-905-7293 | Littleton, CO 80120

Github: https://github.com/AustinWiley

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/austin-wiley-86868416b/
Portfolio: https://wiley-react-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

Skilled engineer with experience in web server development and deployment. Dedicated to improving the development methods used to create new software programs. Built, Deployed and maintain Brewery Software and Server for tracking products, calculating excise taxes and automating processes, increasing productivity and profits. Thanks to years of working in cross-functional teams and running my own business, I'm great at coming up with solutions, no matter what you throw at me.

Technical Skills: Node Js, Javascript ES6, React Js, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Google Firebase, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars Js, Moment.js, NPM, Google Fonts, Font Awesome, Linux, Debian, Ubuntu, Version Control, Deployment, Heroku, Autho Authentication, Bash, Docker, Amazon AWS, Python, Sales Force.

APPLICATIONS BUILT

Docker Boto-3 Github

- Test and copy the contents from one AWS s3 bucket into another s3 bucket using a Python app containerized with Docker.
- Tools/Languages used: Docker, Boto-3, AWS and Python.

IOT Temperature Controller Github / Live

- Node and Express server running on a Debian operating system installed on a headless Raspberry Pi with port forwarding. Developed for use at Spangalang Brewery.
- Tools/Languages used: Javascript ES6, CSS5, Express and Debian os.

Hyperlocal Github / Live

- Hyperlocal is a method for fostering real world connections through shared interests. This app allows you to connect to people in your community.
- Tools/Languages used: Javascript ES6, CSS5, React Js, Bulma, Heroku, Express, Handlebars, Auth o, MongoDB & Mongoose-ODM.

BeerKan Github / Live

- Beer tracking app for the professional brewer and the avid homebrewer that works like a Kanban Board. BeerKan as a digital Brew log allowing the user to track each batch of beer from raw ingredient to keg. Allows the brewer to be more efficient, brew more beer and archive all brewlogs.
- Tools/Languages used: Javascript ES6, CSS5, React Js, Materialize, Heroku, Express, Handlebars, MySQL & Sequelize-ORM.

EDUCATION

University of Denver, Denver, CO

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned consisted of HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars JS, & React Js, PHP, Laravel.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Four Winds Interactive, Denver, CO

June 2019 - Present

Technical Support Specialist

Support clients with FWI software. Perform network troubleshooting on client systems. Troubleshoot FWI software on Android and Web OS. Troubleshoot Windows systems including reviewing system logs and writing batch scripts to automate tasks. As well as perform changes to RegEdit, edit Group Policy, set up file sharing, update drivers, apply software patches to existing software and installing new software. Manage client information through Sales Force.

Spangalang Brewery, Denver, CO

February 2015 - June 2019

Owner Founder Manager and System Administrator

Co-Founded and Operated a successful craft brewery. Created world class beer that won GABF Gold medal and World Beer Cup awards. Managed staff and daily operations of the business including head of Human Resources and Systems Administrator. As Co-Founder, researched local and federal laws and regulations, obtained necessary permits and licenses and managed cross-functional communication between equipment Engineers, Architects, Contractors, and local government.

Denver Beer Co, Denver, CO

February 2014 - February 2015

Head Brewer

Managed Brew house operations and staff during a time of major growth. Maintained Brewery Computers including system updates, hardware setup and troubleshooting for 4 windows machines. Developed and Brewed beer that became a major part of the companies portfolio as well as won nationally recognized awards and medals.

Great Divide Brewing Co, Denver, CO

April 2007 - February 2014

Lead Brewer

Maintained Brewhouse Computers including system updates, hardware setup and troubleshooting. Research and recipe development for award winning beer, team management, staff training, equipment accusation and creating production processes and standards playing a major role in helping the company increase production during a time of rapid growth.